{
  "id": 201,
  "themeId": 2,
  "name": "Writing and Reading Numbers â€“ Quiz 1",
  "description": "Practice Numbers vocabulary and grammar through writing and reading exercises.",
  "version": "2.2.3",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How do you say "10"?",
      "options": ["A. Dix", "B. Dis", "C. Dixe", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Dix",
      "explanation": "The number 10 is often associated with perfection, like in the expression obtenir la note parfaite de dix sur dix (to get the perfect score of ten out of ten)."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "99"?",
      "options": ["A. Quatrevingtdixneuf", "B. Quatre vingt-dix-neuf", "C. Quatre-vingt-dix-neuf", "D. Quatre vingt dix neufs"],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Quatre-vingt-dix-neuf",
      "explanation": "Using hyphens in quatre-vingt-dix-neuf helps avoid confusion with individual numbers. Without hyphens, it could be interpreted as quatre (four), vingt (twenty), dix (ten), and neuf (nine) all separate."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "150"?",
      "options": ["A. Cent-cinquantes", "B. Cents-cinquante", "C. Cents cinquantes", "D. Cent-cinquante"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. Cent-cinquante",
      "explanation": "Hyphens are placed between all the words that make up a number, regardless of its value. This simplified rule has been in effect since 1990."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "100 000"?",
      "options": ["A. Cent-mille", "B. Cents-milles", "C. Cents-mile", "D. Cent-miles"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Cent-mille",
      "explanation": "Mille (thousand) is an invariable noun, meaning it remains in its singular form regardless of the context or the quantity it represents. It never takes a plural ending."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "7 millions"?",
      "options": ["A. Sept million", "B. Sept millions", "C. Septs millions", "D. Septs million"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Sept millions",
      "explanation": "Million s'accorde (agrees) in number when it is used after a number greater than one. This means that the word takes the plural form millions when preceded by a number like deux (two), trois (three), quatre (four), etc."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"80\"?",
      "options": ["A. Quatre-vingts", "B. Quatres-vingts", "C. Quatreu-vingts", "D. Quatre-vingtes"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Quatre-vingts",
      "explanation": "The word vingt (twenty) is written in the plural form only in the number quatre-vingts (four-twenties)."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"5 billion\"?",
      "options": ["A. Cinq milliars", "B. Cinq milliardes", "C. Cinqs milliard", "D. Cinq milliards"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. Cinq milliards",
      "explanation": "Milliard follows the standard pluralization rule for common nouns and has an -s at the end when referring to more than one billion."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"25%\"?",
      "options": ["A. Vingt-cinq pour cents", "B. Vingt-cinq pour cent", "C. Vingt-cinqs pour cents", "D. Vingts-cinq pour cents"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Vingt-cinq pour cent",
      "explanation": "Pour cent means \"per hundred\" or \"percent\" and it indicates that the value is a proportion of a larger quantity, in this case, 100."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"200 ou 210 euros\"?",
      "options": ["A. Deux cents ou deux-cent-dix euros ?", "B. Deux cent ou deux-cent-dix euros ?", "C. Deux cents ou deux-cents-dix euros ?", "D. Deux cents ou deux-cents-dix euro ?"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Deux cents ou deux-cent-dix euros ?",
      "explanation": "Cent does not have an 's' if it is followed by another number."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"les 12 coups de minuit\" ?",
      "options": ["A. les drouze coups de minuit", "B. Les douze coups de minuit", "C. les douces coups de minuit", "D. les douzze coups de minuit"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Les douze coups de minuit.",
      "explanation": "The number 12 is invariable (does not have a plural form)."
    }
  ]
}